Guide to the Arthur Kornberg Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Arthur Kornberg papers
1938-2007
SC0359
Kornberg, Arthur, 1918-2007
52 Linear feet and 400 megabytes
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Arthur Kornberg, 1989, 2002, 2008.
Information about Access
Search files and other personnel files are restricted.
Associated Materials
National Library of Medicine's Profiles in Science
Biography
During a research career spanning more than sixty years, Arthur Kornberg made many outstanding contributions to molecular biology. He was the first to isolate DNA polymerase, the enzyme that assembles DNA from its components, and the first to synthesize DNA in a test tube, which earned him a Nobel Prize in 1959. He later became the first to replicate an infective virus DNA in vitro. He was the primary architect and first chairman of the Department of Biochemistry at the Stanford University School of Medicine, which under his guidance became a preeminent center for DNA research, including recombinant DNA research. Starting in the 1980s, Kornberg also played a key role in establishing productive ties between academic science and the biotechnology industry.
Kornberg was born in Brooklyn, New York on March 3, 1918, the youngest of Joseph and Lena Kornberg's three children. Emigrants from eastern Europe, the Kornbergs owned a small hardware and home furnishings store. Arthur was "an eager and able student" and was allowed to skip grades several times in primary school. He finished high school at age 15, and entered the City College of New York in 1933. Despite this precocity, Kornberg doesn't recall having any early passion for science, or interest in the natural world as a youngster. (He collected matchbook covers rather than butterflies.) He did well in his high school and college chemistry courses, and briefly considered an academic career in the field. During the Depression years, however, medical school seemed a more promising choice. Kornberg received his MD from the University of Rochester in 1941, expecting to become "an internist with academic connections." Following his internship, he began his World War II military service as a ship's doctor on a U.S. Coast Guard vessel in the Caribbean. Though he often quarreled with the ship's captain, Kornberg expected to remain on sea duty for the duration of the war.
Kornberg's career took an unexpected turn when his first medical article was published in 1942. In medical school, Kornberg had conducted a small research study into a disorder (later known as Gilbert syndrome) characterized by excessive bilirubin in the blood and a mild benign jaundice, because he himself had the condition. At the time of publication, senior military medical officers, along with National Institutes of Health (NIH) director Rolla Dyer, were desperately seeking out new information on jaundice, due to an outbreak of jaundice induced by the new yellow fever vaccine. [To learn more about yellow fever vaccine, visit the Wilbur Sawyer Papers on Profiles in Science.] Impressed by Kornberg's study, Dyer arranged his reassignment to a research post in the Nutrition Laboratory at NIH in the fall of 1942. His first project involved tracking down a vitamin deficiency in rats induced by sulfa drugs. Studying the vitamins then known--many of which are coenzymes--Kornberg became intrigued by the central role of enzymes in all living processes, and their immense potential for illuminating the mechanisms of cells. In 1945, desiring to pursue studies of the metabolic enzymes involved in adenosine triphosphate (ATP) production, he received leave to spend a year acquiring further biochemistry training with Severo Ochoa at New York University, and six months with Carl and Gerty Cori at Washington University in St. Louis. It was then, he later recalled, that he began a lifelong love affair with enzymes, the large specialized proteins that catalyze all life processes.
Several years before, Kornberg had married the other love of his life, biochemist Sylvy Ruth Levy. They had met at the University of Rochester and became better acquainted at NIH, where Sylvy was working at the National Cancer Institute. Apart from the six years when their sons Roger, Thomas, and Kenneth were small, Sylvy worked full-time in Kornberg's laboratory throughout their long marriage. The children were often with them there outside of school hours, and two of them, Roger and Thomas, also chose careers in biochemistry. Roger Kornberg went on to receive the 2006 Nobel Prize in Chemistry.
After Kornberg returned to NIH in 1947, he established an Enzyme Section within the Institute of Arthritis and Metabolic Diseases, and continued research into the enzymes involved in metabolic respiration. During the next several years he became very adept at identifying and purifying enzymes, and discovered those that make several key components of metabolic respiration cycles. Encouraged by his success with these systems, he turned his attention to finding the enzyme that assembles various chemical building blocks into the nucleic acids: DNA and RNA. He began by working out the synthesis process for the individual nucleotides, units composed of a nitrogenous base (cytosine, adenine, guanine, uracil, or thymine) combined with a sugar (ribose or deoxyribose) and a phosphate group.
In 1953, Kornberg moved to St. Louis to head the Microbiology Department at Washington University School of Medicine. There he continued working on the synthesis of individual nucleotides, and by 1954 had found the enzymes needed to make all four of the nucleotide building blocks for RNA. A colleague at Washington University had meanwhile found the enzyme that makes the thymine nucleotide (which substitutes for the uracil nucleotide in DNA). Now able to make the building blocks, Kornberg and his colleagues began looking for the enzymes that would put them together into RNA or DNA.
Kornberg focused on the synthesis of DNA after learning in 1955 that Severo Ochoa and his colleagues at NYU had apparently created a synthetic RNA from adenosine diphosphate (ADP) (the product ultimately turned out to be not RNA, but a chain very like it). Working with cell extracts of E. coli bacteria and radioisotope tracers, Kornberg found which combinations of the nucleotides and other ingredients resulted in the most rapid synthesis of DNA. By the following year he had found and purified the essential enzyme, DNA polymerase, from E. coli, and was able to synthesize DNA in the lab. The results were published in 1958, and Kornberg received the 1959 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine (shared with Severo Ochoa) for this work.
Shortly before the Nobel Prizes were announced that year, Kornberg had taken up a new position as chair of the new department of biochemistry at the Stanford University School of Medicine in Palo Alto. Stanford had approached him in 1957, offering the unique opportunity to organize and staff the department from the ground up. Kornberg recruited most of his Washington University faculty and staff, and a number of former postdoctoral fellows for Stanford. Retaining the communal laboratory structure and style that they developed in St. Louis, Stanford's department of biochemistry remained a highly productive, tightly-knit group focused mainly on DNA research. Nearly fifty years later, six of the original faculty--Kornberg, Robert Baldwin, Paul Berg, David Hogness, Dale Kaiser, and Robert Lehman--were still there.
In this stimulating environment, Kornberg and his colleagues continued to identify and delineate the workings of various enzymes involved in DNA replication. In 1967 they synthesized a viable virus DNA, an achievement lauded by the press (to Kornberg's dismay) as the "creation of life in a test tube." They subsequently found enzymes responsible for DNA repair and rearrangement, and others responsible for the start and elongation of DNA chains and chromosomes. The enzymes they discovered, which allowed the manipulation of DNA, helped make possible the development of recombinant DNA technology and the engineering of genes and chromosomes.
In 1991, after many decades of research on DNA replication, Kornberg switched his research focus to inorganic polyphosphate (poly P), a phosphate polymer. Poly P is found in every bacterial, plant and animal cell, but its functions were not well understood. Chemists long regarded it as a molecular fossil, a remnant from earlier evolutionary stages. Kornberg found a variety of likely functions for poly P that include regulating cell responses to stress, and factors responsible for motility and virulence in some of the major disease microorganisms.
In addition to his research and administrative duties, Kornberg also taught graduate, medical, and postdoctoral students. With his own and other Stanford departments so closely involved in the early development of recombinant DNA science, he was long interested in building connections between academic scientists and the emerging biotechnology industry. He was a founding partner of an innovative research institute (DNAX Institute of Molecular and Cellular Biology) in 1980, and served on the advisory boards and councils of many university, governmental, and industrial research institutes.
Kornberg published over three hundred scientific papers during his long career, as well as major monographs on DNA replication, a scientific autobiography, an insider's account of the biotechnology industry, and most recently a children's book, titled Germ Stories, based on stories he told his children and grandchildren over the years.
Besides the 1959 Nobel Prize, Kornberg received numerous other honors, including election to the National Academy of Sciences in 1957, election to the Royal Society of London in 1970, and the National Medal of Science in 1979. He received many honorary doctorates, and in 1999 the University of Rochester dedicated the new Arthur Kornberg Medical Research Building in his honor.
Arthur Kornberg died on October 26, 2007 at the Stanford Hospital, of respiratory failure. He was carrying on his lab research until several days before his death.
Scope and Content
Collection documents Kornberg's work concerning the synthesis of DNA in the laboratory, as well as the synthetic pathways of nucleotides, and includes correspondence, 1947 to 1982; research lab notebooks, 1947 to 1969 (which include those studies for which he received the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 1959); coursework, lectures, and seminars; Stanford University Departmental records; records concerning professional organizations; and reprints, glass research slides, and audiotapes.
Arrangement note
The materials are arrenged in eight series: 1. Correspondence; 2. Research and Laboratory Notebooks; 3. Lectures and Seminars; 4. Professional Files; 5. Class Materials; 6. Stanford Administrative and Departmental Records; 7. Personal and Miscellaneous Papers; 8. Audiovisual materia; and two additions.
Access Terms
Stanford University. School of Medicine. Dept. of Biochemistry--Faculty.; DNA--Synthesis.; Nobel Prize winners; Nobel prize--Stanford faculty--biochemistry
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1947-1987; Series 1
  - Stanford Correspondence, 1957-1975
    - Stanford Correspondence, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Stanford Correspondence, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Stanford Correspondence, Jul-Dec 1958 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Stanford Correspondence A-Co, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Stanford Correspondence Co-Me, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Correspondence Me-R, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Correspondence Sa-Y, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Stanford Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Stanford Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Stanford Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Stanford Correspondence: Medical Search Committee, 1972-1975 (Box 30, Folder 2-4)
    - Library Correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Library Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1947-1987
    - Correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 15, Folder 11-18)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence A-K, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence L-Z, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence A-F, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence G-N, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence O-Z, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence A-L, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence M-Z, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence A-J, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence K-Z, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence A-L, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence M-Z, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence A-C, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence D-K, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence L-R, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence S-Z, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence A-B, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence C-D, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence E-K, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence L-P, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence R-Z, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence A-E, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence F-J, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence K-O, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence P-Z, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence A-F, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence G-H, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence I-M, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence N-Z, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence A-F, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence G-M, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence N-Z, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence A-F, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence G-M, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence N-Z, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence A-F, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence G-P, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence Q-Z, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence A-H, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence I-R, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence S-Z, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence A-B, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence C-I, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence J-Q, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence R-Z, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence A-G, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence F-K, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence L-Q, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence R-XYZ, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence A-E, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence F-K, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence L-Q, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence R-Z, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence A-H, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence I-Z, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence A-C, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence D-I, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence J-P, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Q-S, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence T-Z, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence A-G, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence H-Q, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence R-Z, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence A-E, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence F-J, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence K-R, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence S-Z, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence A-G, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence H-N, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence O-Z, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence A-D, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence E-M, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence N-Z, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Benno C. Schmidt, correspondence and papers, 1974-82 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bellagio Study and Conference Center, correspondence, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - American Professors for Peace in the Middle East, Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Student Reports, DNA, Correspondence, 1961-1969 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Whiting file, Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Special Subjects Correspondence, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 4-8)
    - Journal of Biological Chemistry, Correspondence with, 1953-1962 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Japan, April 1971 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Germany/Israel Trip, Oct-Nov 1971 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Irvine, 1971 Oct (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1968-1972 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Prism magazine, Genetic disease and the Support of Science, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Academic Press, correspondence re: publication of manuscript, included, "Bacterial DNA Polymerases,", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Cranks, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence re: Nobel Lecture, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Sweden, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Political, 1961-1964 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence re: remodeling, 1965-1966 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence MA General Hospital Advisor's Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - ASBC President, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Research and Laboratory Notebooks, 1938-1970; Series 2
  - Pricer Methods (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Ion Exchange [Dataleaflets/Graphs] (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Spectra [Research Notes] (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Medical student notes, 1938-41 (Box 15, Folder 1-10)
  - Lab Notebooks: Berkley Brookhaven Boulder, 1951; 1955; 1958 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Lab Notebooks: Pacific Grove, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Lab Notebooks: SK, 1953-[1957] (Box 16, Folder 11-17)
  - Lab Notebooks: SK Polymerase I & II, 1958; 1958-1959 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Lab Notebooks: Johnson Polymerase, 1961 Dec-1962 Apr (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Lab Notebooks: SK, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Lab Notebooks: New England Enzyme Center: Enzyme Preparations and Fermentations (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
  - Lab Notebooks: PRPP Book 1 [Vancouver], Jan-Feb 1957 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Lab Notebooks: PRPP Book 2 [Vancouver II], Feb 7-Feb 16, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Lab Notebooks: NYU (v. 1-17), 1947-1951 (Box 19)
  - Lab Notebooks: NYU (v. 18-21), 1951-1953 (Box 20)
  - Lab Notebooks: (v. 22-33), 1954-1958 (Box 20)
  - Lab Notebooks: (v. 34-49), 1958-1967 (Box 21)
  - Lab Notebooks: (v. 51-65), 1963-1969 (Box 22)
  - Lab Notebooks: (v. 66-67), 1969 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Lab Notebooks: Radding, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Lab Notebooks: Zimmerman, 1958-1961 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Lab Notebooks: Aposnian, 1959-1962 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Lab Notebooks: Frautner (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Lab Notebooks: Swartz, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Lab Notebooks: Bertsch Em, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Lab Notebooks: Atkinson, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Lab Notebooks: Cozzarelli, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Lab Notebooks: Wehrli, Jackson, Albettson, (1962 and 1964) (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Lab Notebooks: Okazaki, 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Lab Notebooks: Okazaki, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Lab Notebooks: Nussbaum, 1961-1963 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Lab Notebooks: Reichard/Levy/Richardson, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Lectures and Seminars, 1949-1987; Series 3
  - Lectures, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21-32)
  - Lectures, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3-9)
  - Lectures (off campus), 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 16-43)
  - Lectures (off campus), 1975-1981 (Box 4)
  - Lectures/Symposia, 1982-1987 (Box 9, Folder 1-56)
  - Seminars, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Seminars, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Seminars, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Seminars, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Seminars, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Seminars, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Seminars correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Seminars correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Seminars, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Seminars, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Seminars, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Talks, 1948-1957 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Talks, 1959-1980 (Box 18, Folder 1-11)
  - Talks, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Lipkins course, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - St. Louis microbiology lectures, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Enzyme substrate complex (seminar) (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Series of speaking engagements, 1960s-1970s (Box 18, Folder 14-35)
- Professional Files, 1947-1987; Series 4
  - Papers submitted for publication, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence re: publishing book [DNA Synthesis], 1972-79 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Book reviews (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Weizmann Institute, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Senate and House Hearings, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Research support, 1972-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15-19)
  - Research support, 1978-83 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Genetic Engineering, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Genetic Engineering, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Genetic Engineering, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Senator Kennedy letter [re biomedical research and federal funding], 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Weizmann Leadership Conference, Los Angeles, June 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - California Medical Association, Anaheim meeting, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies - Biomedical Workshop, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - ARK Symposium, March 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - National Science Foundation Research Proposal (Membranes in DNA Replications and the Viral Life Cycle), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Aging Grant (DNA Transactions and Aging), 1980-83 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Grants: NSF, NIH, 1978-1983, 1982-1987 (Box 9, Folder 57-60)
  - Professional organizations, misc. files (Box 10, Folder 4-20)
  - Reports, lectures, trips, plans, preparations, 1953-67 (Box 13, Folder 7-26)
  - Miscellaneous research files (Box 15, Folder 19-22)
  - Publications, 1947-52 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Wiesmeyer, Herbert, "The Characterization of the Maltose Permease and Amylomaltose of E. Coli," Ph.D. Thesis Washington University, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - California State Board of Education-Evolution vs. Creation, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - National Academy of Sciences Editorial Board, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - National Academy of Sciences Editorial Board, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - New England Enzyme Center, NIH Panels, reviews, etc. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Notebook of Kornberg's reports "Enzymatic Synthesis of DNA" (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Class Materials, 1953-1968; Series 5
  - Micro-Biology Syllabus, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Micro-Biology Syllabus, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Micro-Biology Syllabus, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Micro-Biology Syllabus, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Micro-Biology Syllabus, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Biochemistry 101-102, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Biochemistry 101-102, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Biochemistry 101-102, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 11)